loomio.org 2019-07-16

# Loomio Privacy Policy | Loomio Help

Updated: 2019-03-21

This privacy policy outlines the information Loomio gathers, how we use it, with whom we share it, and the notices and choices you can expect, regarding your information.

The privacy of your data is our top priority. We will never sell your data or use it for advertising purposes. We only share personal data where necessary to provide our service.

## Non-personally identifiable information

Like most website operators, Loomio collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. We collect non-personally identifying information to understand how our visitors use Loomio, and how to serve them better. From time to time, Loomio may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

## Cookies

Cookies are text files stored on your computer. We store cookies in your browser to identify you when you are using Loomio. We also use cookies to analyse how our website is used and to provide our customer support services. We do not put advertising or social media cookies into Loomio.

## IP addresses

Loomio stores user IP addresses to implement security processes necessary to protect your account.

## User Content and Personally Identifiable Information

As a discussion and decision-making platform, Loomio stores and processes discussions, comments, proposals, outcomes, etc - “user generated content”.

We also store and process your name, email address, profile photo, etc - “your user profile”. This information can make a user personally identifiable, although you are welcome to use a pseudonym and anonymous email address to prevent this.

As a member of a Loomio group, your content including your user profile will be shared with the members of that group. However, your email address will only be available to the group’s coordinators.

Content including your user profile will be public on the internet if you participate in a public discussion or join a public group.

You may view or correct your personal information at any time via the ‘edit profile’ page within Loomio.

You may _deactivate_ your user account. Personally identifying information such as your name, username and profile photo will no longer be associated with content you have posted and Loomio will not contact you again. You are able to reactivate your account at a later date if you wish.

If you wish to _delete_ your user account, you will not be able to reactivate your account at a later date. Your profile information will be permanently deleted from our system.

## Data ownership and deletion of data

Loomio is software used by groups of people to communicate with each other. Over time the record of these communications is an important feature of Loomio.

If you choose to delete your Loomio user account, we will remove your user profile including your user ID, name, email address, profile photo and other known personally identifying information. However, communication history (such as comments and votes) will be kept to preserve the integrity of discussions and decisions within your groups.

If (as a group administrator) you delete a Loomio group, all user data for the group will be deleted.

If you wish to have comments or other data deleted from a group that you are not an administrator of, you should first contact the group administrator and request deletion of that data.

Data deletion requests may be made to the data protection officer via email (dpo@loomio.org). Loomio may delete user data at the request of law enforcement or if personal safety is at risk.

## Data Security, Integrity and Access

Loomio will not sell or rent any information you share with us. Access to your content and personally identifiable information is tightly controlled. Loomio takes all reasonable steps to protect your content from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

Content entered into the platform is distributed to the appropriate members of your groups, via secure connections where possible, and sent via email in the normal course of operation.

From time to time, our team members may access your contact details to send you information about Loomio, services provided by Loomio’s partners, or to ask for feedback. If you do not wish to receive these emails, please respond with a request to be taken off the contact list, or unsubscribe by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.

Loomio Co-operative Limited has GDPR compliant data processing agreements in place with all data processors used to provide our services.

To learn more about the data processors used in the course of providing Loomio please see our GDPR page.

## Loomio Terms of Service and Service Level Agreements

Our standard terms of service are not offered as an SLA (Service Level Agreement) at this time. They are governed by the Terms of Service.

Under these terms, Loomio makes no guarantee of availability. Loomio’s standard service is for general use. Loomio software can be set up on a separate private installation and a Service Level Agreement established if required by a customer, at an additional charge. Customers requiring enterprise-level service managed under an SLA are encouraged to [contact us](https://www.loomio.org/contact) for further information.

## Changes

We will always maintain the overriding principle that we will not sell or rent any information you share with us. However, we may change other aspects of this policy. Any amended policy is effective upon posting to this website, and we’ll make every effort to tell you about these changes via email or through the site.

Thanks for taking the time to learn about our privacy policy. We feel it’s increasingly important for people to know exactly how their information is treated online, so we’ve tried to make the policy as clear and specific as possible. If you have any questions or concerns, please [contact us](https://www.loomio.org/contact).
